让我们退后一步，眯着眼睛看目前为止的代码
let's step back and squint at the code we have so far
查看此客户端服务器交互
looking at this client server interaction
我们看到两种风格的代码
we see two flavors of code
所有消息通用的代码
code that's common to all messages
和特定于消息的代码
and code that's specific to a message
在客户端界面方面
in terms of the client interface
所有三个函数都向服务器发送消息
all three functions send a message to the server
然后等待收到回复
and then wait to receive a response
接收块一开始是特定的
the receive block at first appear specific
但是这些变量名是任意的
but these variable names are arbitrary
所以我们可以使这些块通用
so we can make these blocks generic
只需将变量重命名为响应
simply by renaming the variable to response
现在
now the
唯一特定于每个的东西
only thing that specific to each
函数是实际的消息
function is the actual message
那是发送的
that's sent
怎么办
now what
关于监听循环中的代码
about the code in the listen loop that
在服务器进程中运行良好
runs in the server process well
需要注意的一件事是所有预期的消息都有
one thing to notice is that all expected messages have
发件人作为第一个元素
sender as the first element
每个子句也以做同样的两件事结束
also each clause ends by doing the same two things
他们将响应消息发送回发件人
they send a response message back to the sender
然后与状态递归循环
and then recursively loop with the state
在处理下一条消息时使用
to be used when handling the next message
在创建承诺的情况下
in the case of creating a pledge
响应包括 id
the response includes id
状态是更新的现金
and the state is the updated cash
在获得最近的承诺的情况下
in the case of getting recent pledges
响应包括状态
the response includes the state
这是承诺清单
which is the list of pledges
并且由于状态没有改变
and since the state didn't change
循环的下一次迭代使用当前状态
the next iteration of the loop uses the current state
并且在获得总质押的情况下
and in the case of getting the total pledge
响应包括总金额
the response includes the total amount
并且状态不变
and the state is unchanged
现在你可以想象
now you can imagine that
每次你介绍一个新消息
every time you introduce a new message
你需要写更多的这个泛型来处理
you'll need to write more of this generic to handle
客户端服务器交互的底层细节
the low level details of client server interaction
但肯定长生不老药不会让我们这样做
but surely elixir wouldn't make us do that
像这样编写大量的服务器进程是
writing spadeful server processes like this is
如此普遍以至于实际上有一个抽象
so common that there's actually an abstraction
gen server 代表通用服务器进程
gen server which stands for generic server process
封装通用代码
encapsulates the generic code
这对于 spadeful 服务器进程很常见
that's common to spadeful server processes
这样
and that way
我们可以专注于编写应用程序特定的代码
we can focus on writing the application specific code
所以我们可以转换我们的质押服务器
so we could convert our pledge server
此时直接到 gen 服务器
straight to a gen server at this point
但如果我们实现这一飞跃
but if we make that leap
gen server 将拍摄魔法
gen server is going to film magical
可能太神奇了
probably too magical
是的
yeah instead
我们想重构我们的
we want to refactor our
代服务器风格的代码
code towards the gen server style
到最后，一个 gen server 就会崩溃
and by the end a gen server will just sort of fall out
你会有更好的
and you'll have a better
了解它在后台是如何工作的
understanding of how it works under the hood
让我们从删除重复开始
let's start by removing the duplication
在这些客户端接口函数中
in these client interface functions
是的，我们将尝试帮助我们封装的方法
yeah we'll try to help our method that encapsulates to
在这些内部发送和接收步骤
send and receive steps inside of these
所以我要继续复制其中一个
so I'm just going to go ahead and copy one of these
随身携带
and take it with us
我们要在这里找到一个函数
we're going to find a function down here
被叫调用认为远程过程调用
called call think remote procedure call
这是一个同步请求
it's a synchronous request
它向服务器发送消息
it sends a message to the server
然后等待我们的回应
and then waits for our response
并且性别将同步请求称为调用
and gender refers to synchronous requests as calls
所以我们会效仿
so we'll follow suit
然后粘贴在那件外套上
then just paste in that coat
现在让它更通用
and let's make it more generic now
所以电话需要接听
so call is going to need to take a
pid和一条消息
pid and a message
我们将发送给那个pid
and we're going to send to that pid
消息，以便我们可以删除此特定消息
the message so we can remove this specific message
它只是传递进来的任何消息
it's just going to be whatever message gets passed in
并且self必须永远是第一个
and self must always be the first
消息元素
element of the message
这个功能负责
and this function takes care of
确保这总是正确的
making sure that's always true
然后在接收块中
and then in the receive block
我们将把响应标记为
we're going to tag the response as
响应是一个原子
response which is an atom
然后我们将绑定
and then we're just going to bind
对通用变量的响应
the response to a generic variable
我们只是打电话给响应
we're just going to call response
所以现在让我们改变
so now let's change
要使用的客户端接口函数
the client interface functions to use
我们的新调用函数
our new call function
所以我们将从删除此接收行开始
so we'll start by removing this receive line
我将在所有功能中删除它
I'll just remove that in all the functions
因为 call 为我们做到了
because call does that for us
然后而不是打电话
and then instead of calling
cind 在这里我们想打电话
cind right here we want to call
打电话，我们会通过名字
call and we'll pass it at name
这就是我们服务器进程的坑
that's the pit of our server process
然后就消息而言
and then in terms of the message
我们不需要包括
we don't need to include
self 是第一个元素，因为
self is the first element because the
调用函数负责处理
call function takes care of that
好的，这条消息是一个工具
okay and this message is a tootle
所以我们周围有卷发
so we've got curlies around it
但我们不需要围绕这些卷曲
but we don't need curlies around these
因为他们只是亚当斯
because they're just adams
所以我会删除那些
so I'll remove those
现在如果我们往下看接收到的块
now if we look down in the received block of
后循环在这里
mizzen loop down here
你注意到
you notice that
这个伟大的承诺信息
this great pledge message
好吧，它不是卷曲的，但这里的这个是
well it's not in curly's but this one up here is
所以我们需要确保将它嵌套在 curly 中
so we need to make sure to nest this in curly's
就在这里
right down here
把它保存起来，如果我们运行它
save that away and if we run it
好吧，它就像以前一样工作
well it works just like before
但现在我们已经删除了重复项
but now we've removed the duplication
在那些爬升的接口函数中
in those climbed interface functions
现在在监听循环中
now down in the listen loop
我们想分开
we want to separate the
来自应用程序特定代码的公共代码
common code from the application specific code
并做到这一点
and to do that
让我们在
let's add a generic clause to the
接收循环的顶部
top of the received loop
因为所有预期的消息都具有相同的基本模式
since all expected messages have the same basic pattern
是的，他们从发件人开始
yeah they start with a sender
然后是消息的其余部分
and then there's the rest of the message
每个爪子都以做同样的两件事而告终
in each claws ends by doing the same two things
他们向发件人发送响应
they send a response to the sender
所以它发送发件人
so it send sender
消息看起来像这样
and the message looks like this
回应，然后有一些回应
response and then there's some response
与之相关的
associated with that
然后他们递归地调用监听循环
and then they recursively call listen loop
与国家
with the state
在循环的下一次迭代中使用
to be used in the next iteration of the loop
每个子句还具有特定于消息的代码
each clause also has message specific code
所以这里有一些特定的消息
so here's some message specific
创建承诺的代码
code for creating a pledge
总承诺在那里进行计算
total pledges does a computation right there
我们不希望接收循环中的任何代码
and we don't want any of that code in the receive loop
我们希望循环是通用的
we want the loop to be generic
没问题
well that's no problem
我们知道有条件地运行代码的方法
we know a way to conditionally run code
基于模式匹配
based on pattern matches
我们可以使用多子句函数
we can use multi clause functions
是的，我们会把它放在这个监听循环下面
yeah we'll put it below this listen loop
我们将函数命名为处理下划线调用
and we'll name the functions handle underscore call
因为他们处理同步调用
because they handle the synchronous call
我们从客户那里得到
we got from the client
然后他们会接受两个参数的消息
and then they're going to take two arguments a message
和国家
and the state
我们需要一个
and we're going to need a
对于每个特定的消息，这样的函数子句
function clause like this for every specific message
所以让我们从底部开始，一路向上
so let's start from the bottom and work our way up 1st
我们需要一个匹配的句柄调用函数子句
we need a handle call function clause that matches
认捐总额
total pledges
所以这将是信息
so that's going to be the message
我就贴在那里
I'll just paste that there
然后我们将获取消息特定代码
and then we'll take the message specific code
并将其粘贴为函数的主体
and paste it in as the body of the function
现在这个函数返回总数
and now this function returns the total
这是我们要发送的响应
which is the response that we want to send
回到客户端进程
back to the client process
所以现在如果我们回到我们的通用爪子这里
so now if we go back up into our generic claws here
我们需要做的是调用句柄调用
what we need to do is invoke handle call
将当前状态的消息传递给它
pass it the message in the current state
它会回来的
it's going to return
我们应该发回给客户的东西
the thing that we should send back to the client
所以我们要绑定它
so we're going to bind that
到一个称为响应的变量
to a variable called response
然后我们在消息中包含响应
and then we include the response in the message
在那里
right there
现在你注意到我们刚刚传递了这部分信息
now you notice we just passed this part of the message
进入处理调用
into handle call
我们不必传入发件人
we didn't have to pass the sender in
因为发件人是在线使用的
because the sender is used on the line
处理呼叫后发送回发件人
after handle call to send back to the sender
所以所有处理呼叫需求都是消息的这一部分
so all handle call needs is this part of the message
所以现在我们可以删除总认捐的这个条款
so now we can remove this clause for total pledges
因为通用子句负责
because the generic clause takes care of that
接下来我们需要一个函数子句
next we need a function clause that
匹配最近的承诺信息
matches the recent pledges message
好的，我们将复制该消息
all right we'll copy that message
在句柄调用函数子句中
at a handle call function clause
这将是信息
that's going to be the message
也必须采取
also has to take the
状态
state
那么在这种情况下的反应是什么
so what's the response in this case
客户想要最近的承诺
well the client wants the recent pledges
所以我们只返回整个状态
so we just return the entire state
这就是我们想要发回给客户端的响应
that's the response we want to send back to the client
现在我们可以移除最近的承诺爪
and now we can remove the recent pledges claws
因为我们的通用爪子在顶部
because our generic claws at the top
会处理的
is going to take care of that
然后最后
and then last
但同样重要的是，我们需要一个
but not least we need a
匹配 create 的第三个函数子句
third function clause that matches the create
承诺信息
pledge message
好的
all right
处理呼叫
handle call
有消息
there's the message
有状态
there's the state
然后我要回去接收消息
then I'm going to go back up and get the message
具体代码
specific code
这是发送前的一切
it's everything before the send
所以我就复制一下
so I'll just copy that
好的，那么在这种情况下的反应是什么
okay so what's the response in this case
好吧，我们想返回这个 id
well we want to return this id
那个id是绑定的
that id is bound
由于调用了这个罪的誓言来服务
as a result of calling this sin pledge to service
所以它是任何 id
so it's whatever id
发回给我们的外部服务
the external service sent back to us
所以我们把它放在函数的最后一行
so we'll just put that on the last line the function
然后它会被退回
and then it'll get returned
然后那个id
and then that id
将是发回的响应的一部分
will be part of the response that sent back
给客户
to the client
然后我们可以在接收到的循环中删除该子句
and then we can remove that clause in our received loop
因为我们的通用条款正在处理那个
because our generic clause is taking care of that one
现在也是
now too
好的，让我们运行它
okay so let's run it
好吧，这不太对
well that's not quite right
我们看
we see
承诺是在外部服务中创建的
that the pledges were created in the external service
但是我们的现金是空的，我们的总数为零
but our cash is empty and our total is zero
那是因为创造
and that's because create
质押改变当前状态
pledge transforms the current state
进入新状态
into a new state
但一般条款
but the generic clause
总是以当前状态重复出现
is always recurring with the current state
是的，如果句柄调用更新状态
yeah if handle call updates the state
传递给它
that gets passed to it
然后我们需要用那个新状态重复
then we need to recurs with that new state
所以我们会改变
so we'll change
处理调用以始终在元组中返回两件事
handle call to always return two things in a tuple
首先
the first
事情将是我们想要发回的响应
thing will be the response that we want to send back
给客户
to the client
第二个
and the second
事情会是
thing will be
我们想要重现的新状态
the new state that we want to recurs with
所以我们需要将这里的状态更改为新状态
so we need to change state here to new state
现在让它工作
now for that to work
我们需要改变我们的功能
we need to change our function
爪子在这里返回
claws down here to return
两件事第一件事就是id
two things the first thing is going to be the id
这就是我们想要发回给客户端的响应
that's the response we want to send back to the client
但我们也想返回新的状态
but we also want to return the new state
所以我们在那里返回一个元组
so we're returning a tuple there
这样当我们将状态转换为新状态时
that way when we transform the state to the new state
我们把它还回来
we return that back
以同样的方式
in the same way
我们需要在
we need to return a two element tuple in the
其他句柄调用
other handle call
功能从句
function clauses
所以对于总认捐
so for total pledged
我们想把总数发回给客户
we want to send back the total to the client
然后我们将与国家重演
and then we were going to recurs with the state
因为我们没有改变状态
because we haven't changed the state
我们只是要返回现有的状态
we're just going to return the existing state
然后是最近的承诺
and then for recent pledges
我们想回来
we want to return
这个状态给客户端
this state to the client
因为国家有所有的承诺和
because the state has all the pledges and
他们要求所有最近的承诺
they're asking for all the recent pledges
我们也想用那个状态重新诅咒
and we also want to re curse with that state
所以这个元组有
so this tuple has
两个都是状态的元素
two elements that are both state
保存并运行它
save it away and run it
嘿，现在可以了
hey and that now works
现在我们注释掉了
now we commented out the line that has
我们意想不到的信息
our unexpected message
如果我们现在把它放回去并运行它
if we put that back in now and run it
好吧，我们得到一个错误
well we get an error
是的，它说没有功能爪匹配
right it says there's no function claws matching
它正在尝试调用句柄调用函数
it's trying to call the handle call function
用锤子时间
with hammer time
那是因为这条消息将匹配我们的
well that's because this message is going to match our
通用消息爪
generic message claws
它认为这是发件人，这是消息
it thinks this is the sender and this is the message
所以如果我们再看看我们的通用爪子就在这里
so up here if we look at our generic claws again
所以这个模式将匹配停止
so this pattern is going to match stop
锤击时间
hammer time
这将尝试调用句柄调用
and this is going to try to call handle call
用锤子时间
with hammer time
这就是为什么我们得到那种空气
which is why we get that air
没有与该消息匹配的功能爪
there's no function claws that matches that message
所以要解决这个问题，我们将添加一个保护爪
so to fix this we're going to add a guard claws
这个模式就在这里
to this pattern right here
我要说 pid sender 是什么时候
I'm going to say when is pid sender
所以这就是说这应该只匹配
so that's saying this should only match
如果这个元组的第一个元素中有什么
if whatever is in the first element of this tuple
是一个pid，我们使用愚蠢的函数并传入sender
is a pid we use the stupid function and pass in sender
这样它就不会匹配
that way it won't match
停止我们意外消息中的原子
stop the atom that we have in our unexpected message
只有当这是一个 pid 时才会匹配
it will only match if this is a pid
现在可以了
and now that works
现在您的应用中可能会出现一些情况
now there may be situations in your app
您要向服务器进程发送消息的位置
where you want to send a message to a server process
但您无需等待回复
but you don't need to wait for a reply
基本上你想开火
basically you want to fire off
向服务器发送消息，然后忘记它
a message to the server and then forget about it
所以现在让我们看一个简单的例子
so let's look at a simple example for now
稍后我们将看一个更复杂的示例
later we'll look at a more involved example
假设我们想要能够清除的选项
let's suppose we want the option of being able to clear
拿出现金，这样我们就可以像一个清晰的函数一样调用
out the cash so we could call like a clear function
是的，假设我们有一个质押服务器
yeah let's assume we have a pledge server
像这样清除功能
clear function like that
所以让我们继续执行它
so let's go ahead and implement that
客户端接口函数
client interface function
我会把它放在这里
I'll put it right up here
所以它需要做的就是发送
so all it needs to do is send
到我们的服务器处理消息清除
to our server process the message clear
与其他客户端接口功能相比
and in contrast to the other client interface functions
clear 是同步的
clear is a synchronous
它只是向服务器发送一条消息，然后
it just fires off a message to the server and
因为它不需要等待响应
since it doesn't need to wait for a response
它几乎立即返回
it returns almost immediately
现在你可以想象一个场景
now you can imagine a scenario where you have
超过一个
more than one
简单地发送这样的消息的函数
function that simply sends a message like this
所以就像我们写了一个调用帮助函数一样
so in the same way that we wrote a call helper function
封装同步请求
that encapsulates synchronous requests
相似地
similarly
我们可以编写一个辅助函数来封装
we can write a helper function that encapsulates
同步请求
a synchronous request
只是为了对称
just for symmetry
所以我要在这里发表评论
so I'm going to put a comment here
这是辅助功能
here are helper functions
并在电话下方
and down below call
将定义一个新函数
will define a new function
我要称之为演员表
I'm going to call it cast
想想这就像把信息扔给风
think of this like casting the message to the wind
这是一个e同步请求
it's an e synchronous request
它向服务器发送消息
it sends a message to the server
并且不期望得到回应
and doesn't expect a response
所以它需要一个pid和一个消息
so it's going to take a pid and a message
这将发送
and this is going to send
给那个坑的信息
the message to that pit
然后我们可以将 clear 更改为而不是调用 send
then we can change clear to instead of calling send
它只会调用 cast
it's just going to call cast
现在这并没有给我们带来多少好处
now that didn't buy us much
除了一些更名和一些墓地
other than some renaming and some cemetery
但和我们待一会儿
but hang with us for a minute
然后在我们收到的块中
then in our received block
我们可以处理那个明确的信息
we can handle that clear message
我会把它放在这里
I'll put it right here
清除
clear
我们需要做的就是
and all we need to do is
将状态重置为空列表
reset the state to an empty list
所以新的状态
so the new state
将是一个像那样的空列表
is just going to be an empty list like that
然后我们需要以那个新状态递归
and then we need to recurs with that new state
客户不期望响应，所以我们不发送
the client doesn't expect a response so we don't send
什么回来
anything back
所以如果我们说完然后运行它
so if we say that away and we run it
虽然它有效
while it works
现在我们最近的承诺
now our recent pledges
只包括恩典，因为我们清除了它
just includes grace because we cleared it
其他一切都消失了
and everything else was gone
然后我们为最近的承诺增添了恩典
and then we added grace to the recent pledges
但假设你有不止一个
but suppose you have more than one of these
并且您想要一种通用的方式来处理
and you want a generic way to handle a
同步消息
synchronous messages
很好地做到这一点
well to do that
让我们在接收循环中添加另一个通用子句
let's add another generic clause to the receive loop
而且这里的消息模式永远不会有发件人
and the message pattern here will never have a sender
只是一条消息
just a message
异步消息子句
an asynchronous message clauses
只需要递归调用
only need to recursively call
监听状态循环
listen loop with the state
我们将在另一个中处理消息特定代码
we'll take care of the message specific code in another
多子句功能
multi clause function
这将命名句柄演员
which will name handle cast
因为它处理同步请求
because it handles a synchronous request
客户端发送的
sent by the client
它需要在当前状态下接收消息
it needs to take a message in the current state
然后返回新状态
and then return the new state
然后它将以那个新状态重现
then it's going to recurs with that new state
所以不像处理调用
so unlike handle call
处理
handle
cast 不需要为客户端返回响应
cast doesn't need to return a response for the client
因为客户不期望一个
because the client doesn't expect one
所以现在让我们定义句柄转换
so now let's define handle cast
我们只有一条演员信息要处理
we only have one cast message to handle
所以我们只需要一个功能爪
so we only need one function claws
信息很明确
the message is clear
那么第二个参数是状态
then the second argument is state
但我们不会使用状态
but we're not going to use the state
所以我要使用下划线状态
so I'm going to use underscore state
所以我们不会收到警告
so we don't get a warning
然后我们需要做的就是返回新的状态
and then all we need to do is return the new state
好吧，在这种情况下，这只是一个空列表
well that's just an empty list in this case
所以现在我们可以移除这个爪子
so now we can remove this claws
因为我们的通用爪子就在这里
because our generic claws right here
处理那个
handles that
所以现在如果我们把它保存起来并运行它
so now if we save that away and we run it
哦，我们得到另一个错误
oh we get another error
这是没有功能爪匹配错误
it's the no function claws matching error
但这次是试图调用句柄演员
but this time is trying to call handle cast
带停锤时间
with stop hammer time
那是因为停止锤击时间
and that's because stop hammer time
将在此处匹配此模式消息
will match this pattern right here message
因为它只是一个变量
because it's just a variable
它会吸收
it's going to soak up
无论我们在这里收到什么信息
whatever message we get right here
记住模式从上到下匹配
remember patterns are matched top to bottom
并且所有意想不到的消息都会得到匹配
and all unexpected messages are going to get matched
此模式消息为时过早
too early by this pattern message
所以我们需要一种方法来匹配呼叫和投射消息
so we need a way to match call and cast messages
但是然后让
but then let
其他一切都属于意外条款
everything else fall through to the unexpected clause
要做到这一点
to do that
我们将消息标记为呼叫
we're going to tag the messages as either being a call
或演员表，我们将通过添加
or a cast and we'll do that by adding an
消息元组的元素
element to the message tuple
所以我们将在那里进行原子调用
so we'll have the atom call right there
我们将在这个元组中投射原子
and we'll have the atom cast inside of this tuple
现在让它工作
now for this to work
客户端必须发送带有这些标签的消息
the client must send messages with these tags
没问题
well that's no problem
因为我们已经有了
because we already have
这些辅助函数调用 encase
these helper functions call encase
使用的
that are used
通过客户端接口函数发送消息
by the client interface functions to send messages
所以打电话
so in call
我们只是将原子调用添加到该消息中
we just add the atom call right there to that message
并且 in cast 会改变它的信息
and in cast will change its message
自动标记那些
to automatically tag those
所以现在演员是
so now cast is
实际上拉了一些重量
actually pulling some weight
通过为我们标记消息
by tagging the messages for us
是的，很好的是我们不必改变
yeah and what's nice is we don't have to change
这些客户端接口函数中的任何一个
any of these client interface functions
因为打电话
because the call
和 cast 辅助函数做标记
and cast helper functions do the tagging
如果我们把它保存起来，它应该可以工作，而且确实可以
if we save that away it should work and indeed it does
所以让我们退后一步
so let's step back
并将对所有人通用的东西分开
and separate what's generic to all
服务器进程以及特定于此
server processes and what's specific to this
特定的服务器进程
particular server process
是的，让我们继续，从这里的顶部开始
yeah let's just go ahead and start at the top here
所以这些客户端接口功能就在这里
so these client interface functions right here
专门用于质押
are specific to pledging
但是这些辅助功能在这里
but these helper functions down here
虽然它们是通用的
while they're generic
客户端接口函数使用它们来发送
they're used by the client interface functions to send
呼叫或发送消息
call or cast messages
所以让我们继续把它们移到一个新模块中
so let's go ahead and move these into a new module
我只是要把它放在顶部
and I'm just going to put it at the top
这里的文件
of the file here
只是这样更容易在 sublime 中运行
just so it's easier to run inside of sublime
我们将调用模块调查
and we're going to call the module survey
通用服务器
generic server
我就粘贴进去
and I'll just paste in
那些辅助功能
those helper functions
然后在质押服务器中关闭
then down in pledge server
我们将为该模块起别名
we're going to alias that module in
然后在我们的客户端界面功能下
and then down in our client interface functions
我们在这里有电话
where we have the call right here
好吧，这只是通用服务器
well that's just going to be generic server
现在打电话
call now
因为那是定义调用函数的地方
because that's where the call function is defined
以同样的方式铸造
in the same way for cast
我们被称为通用服务器演员
we're called generic server cast
如果我们保存它并运行它
if we save that away and we run it
毫不奇怪，它就像以前一样工作
well no surprise it works just as it did before
接下来是这个监听循环就在这里
next up is this listen loop right here
它也是通用的
and it's also generic
什么也没有
there's nothing
完全关于此代码的应用程序
application specific about this code at all
应用程序特定代码
the application specific code
生活在这些多子句功能中
lives in these multi clause functions
处理调用和处理转换
handle call and handle cast
你需要包含这个通用循环函数
you'd need to include this generic loop function in
一种或另一种形式
one form or another
编写任何服务器进程时
when writing any server process
所以让我们继续移动它
so let's go ahead and move it
也进入通用服务器模块
into the generic server module as well
所以现在当监听循环收到一条消息时
so now when listen loop receives a message
它需要调用相应的句柄调用
it needs to invoke the corresponding handle call
或处理强制转换功能
or handle cast function
这是在质押服务器模块中，所以这需要
that's in the pledge server module so this needs to be
民意调查
survey
以同样的方式处理呼叫
handle call in the same way
我们需要在该模块上调用句柄转换
we need to call handle cast on that module
现在回到我们的质押服务器模块
now going back down to our pledge server module
我们还能搬什么
what else could we move
有几个小改动
well with a couple minor changes
我们可以移动这个启动函数
we could move this start function
到我们的通用服务器
of to our generic server
我只是要复制它
I'm just going to copy it
我们会把它贴在这里
and we'll paste it up here
我们将首先删除它
we'll remove this first
io dot 放我们是因为我们没有开始承诺
io dot put us because we're not starting the pledge
服务器这是更通用的
server this is more generic
并且因为这
and since this
下划线下划线模块
underscore underscore module
下划线 下划线将扩大
underscore underscore will expand
到将被服务的当前模块
to the current module which would be serviced
在这种情况下是通用服务器
generic server in this case
好吧，这条线将继续并产生
well this line is going to go ahead and spawn
我们必须找到的监听循环
the listen loop that we have to find
在这个模块里面
inside this module
所以这一切都很好
so that's all good
但是这个名字是特定于一个进程的
but this at name is specific to a process
和这个初始状态
and this initial state
在这种情况下是一个空列表
which in this case is an empty list
特定于一个进程
is specific to a process
所以要使这个启动功能通用
so to make this start function generic
我们需要传入这两件事
we're going to need to pass in these two things
作为参数，我们将传入初始状态
as argument so we'll pass in the initial state
这是第一个论点
it's the first argument
然后第二个将是名称
and then the second one will be the name
然后我们将在这里替换一个空列表
and then we'll substitute here instead of an empty list
这将是初始状态
it's going to be initial state
接着
and then
而不是使用 at name 我们只是要使用 name
instead of using at name we're just going to use name
然后在我们的插件服务器的启动功能中下来
then down in the start function of our plug server
在这里，我们不必再做这些事情了
right here we don't have to do this stuff anymore
我们可以调用通用服务器启动
we can just call generic server start
然后传入这个进程的初始状态
and then pass in this process's initial state
这是一个空列表，然后是名称
which is an empty list and then the name
我们的名字
which we have in at name
保存并运行它
save that away and run it
这同样有效
and that works just the same
现在一切
and now everything
质押服务器中的 else 特定于质押
else in pledge server is specific to pledging
但如果我们回到我们的
but if we go back to our
通用服务器并查看监听循环
generic server and look in the listen loop
好吧，我们有硬涂层承诺服务器
well we've hard coated pledge server
真正成为通用的通用服务器应该与
to truly be generic generic servers should work with
任何模块
any module
只要那个模块实现了这两个功能
as long as that module implements the two functions
处理调用和处理转换
handle call and handle cast
我们希望通用服务器回调
we want the generic server to call back
到我们的质押服务器模块运行
to our pledge server module to run
应用程序特定代码
the application specific code
换句话说，质押服务器
in other words pledge server
是我们的回调模块
is to be our callback module
我们将有一个名为回调模块的变量
we'll have a variable called callback module that
保留该回调模块
holds onto that callback module
然后我们会打电话
and then we'll call
处理该模块上的强制转换和处理调用
handle cast and handle call on that module
那么我们将如何提供这个回调模块
so how are we going to feed this callback module
进入通用服务器
into the generic server
好吧，首先在我们的开始功能中
well first down in our start function here
当我们启动通用服务器时，我们需要告诉它
when we start the generic server we need to tell it
哪个模块实现了回调函数
which module implements the callback functions
我们将回调模块作为第一个传递
and we'll pass the callback module as the first
争论
argument
现在回调
now the callback
实现回调函数的模块
module that implements the callback functions
这个模块是
is this module
这是质押服务器模块
it's the pledge server module
所以我们可以再次使用这个技巧
so we can use this trick again
所以我们告诉通用服务器
so we're telling the generic server
我们是当前模块
that we are the current module
质押服务器模块
the pledge server module
回调模块在哪里
where the callback module
现在让它工作
now for that to work
我们需要改变
we need to change
这里的启动功能
the start function up here
在通用服务器中
in generic server to
将该回调模块作为第一个参数
take that callback module as the first argument
然后最终我们需要将它传递给这个
and then ultimately we need to pass it down to this
听循环，我们会记住 spawn 的第三个参数
listen loop we'll remember the third argument to spawn
是要发送到的参数列表
is a list of arguments to send to
生成的函数
the function that's getting spawned
在这种情况下，它是监听循环
in this case it's listen loop
所以现在
so right now
监听循环只接受一个参数作为初始状态
listen loop just takes one argument the initial state
但我们可以传递第二个参数
but we can pass it a second argument that's
将成为我们的回调模块
going to be our callback module
然后在监听循环中
then down in listen loop
我们将在那里有回调模块
we'll have callback module there
并且由于这个功能现在
and since this function now
接受两个我们知道的论点
takes two arguments we know
我们将不得不重复这些相同的
we're going to have to recurs with those same
两个论点
two arguments
所以我们将在那里传递回调模块
so we're going to have callback module passed there
那里和那里
there and also there
保存并运行它
save that away and run it
嘿，很酷，这也有效
hey cool that works too
谁
who
所以现在通用服务器封装了所有
so now generic server encapsulates all
服务器进程通用的通用代码
the generic code that's common to server processes
它依赖于回调模块
it relies on a callback module
比如pled服务器模块
such as the pled server module
实现应用程序特定的代码
to implement the application specific code
在回调函数中处理调用和句柄
in the callback functions handle call and handles
所以在我们的质押服务器中
so down here in our pledge server
我们可以更改此评论
we can change this comment
服务器就在这里
server right here
到服务器回调
to server callbacks
因为这些只是被调用的回调
because these are just callbacks that are called by
我们的通用服务器
our generic server
现在我们处于一个伟大的
and now we're in a great
开始使用 gen 服务器抽象的位置
position to start using the gen server abstraction
接下来是
and it's up next